

kate.vonhouck.com kate@vonhouck.com

ABOUT ME

Hey, Kate here. I have experience working on successful business software at Microsoft. I have shipped many different products including complex site diagnostic tools, business dashboards, flow diagrams, data visualization, and easy to use account sign up flows.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Microsoft / User Experience, Product Designer - Contractor

Redmond, WA | July 2019 - Present

- · Redesigned SharePoint template gallery.
- · Designed webpage speed and weight diagnostic tools.
- · Worked on Power BI and SharePoint Integration.
- Experimented with onboarding and learning experiences.
- · Created many data visualization dashboards.
- · Brought together a disperate team to deliver the unified product.

Istrolid 2 computer game / Freelance UX/UI Designer

San Francisco, CA | May 2018 - March 2019

- · Visual design for game interfaces and hierarchy of game screens.
- Experience design for the main menu and widgets.

Waterpark / Freelance Visual Designer

San Francisco, CA | August 2018 - August 2018

· Logo design, icon design, and branding.

Gravitational Inc / UX Designer

Oakland, CA | October 2017 - April 2018

- · Primary designer at Gravitational Inc.
- · Designed the company and product logos.
- · Created the visual design language with a full icon set.
- UX/UI design for open source documentation.

EDUCATION

Academy of Art University

San Francisco, CA | January 2014 - May 2017

Bachelor of Web Design & New Media

City College of San Francisco

San Francisco, CA | January 2011 - January 2014

General Education in Business

Altai State University

Barnaul, Russia | September 2007 - May 2009

Associate of Asian Studies

SKILLS

Software

Figma

Sketch

Invision

Adobe CS

Keynote

Power BI

SharePoint

Design

Storyboarding

Wireframing

Prototyping

Branding

Data Visualization

Visual Design

Interaction Design

Motion Design

Style Guides

Research

Persona

User Interviews

Usability Testing

Competitive Analysis

A/B Testing

Experiments

Task Analysis

Persona Hypothesis

Programming

HTML/CSS

JavaScript

Swift

Languages

English

Russian

Mandarin